thirty minutes past 6:00 p.m. Monday
evening we're back again with something
very exciting something that will make
you go happy by end of this episode
welcome to the fourth episode of
wellness 360 at home
brought to you by I see a yellow bar
live on zoom' live on Facebook live on
Instagram as well
my name is Bettina Pavia and happy and
very delighted to have all the people
watching us right now but it's going to
be a fit and fine evening
I promise you that so who is joining us
today
well somebody who is a fitness expert
with about 29 years of experience in the
fitness industry and pioneer of Pilates
physical fitness system in India she's
earned a reputation of being the number
one celebrity trainer with her client in
enlisting the creme de la creme of
Bollywood like katrina kaif typica
Padukone alia Bhatt Preity Zinta the
pasta bar soo Nora Fatih he vaani Kapoor
sophia chaudhary Ananya Pandey Khushi
Kapoor to name a few apart from this is
also the first balanced body master
Pilates instructor and pleasure Pilates
instructor in India give a delighted to
welcome here at wellness 360 at home the
one only yasmeen Karachi wallah with us
right now
hi and all of you while watching us
I'm doing good yes we'll have you doing
in how the current I'm treating you
oh it's been great there's a lot of
things happening like I'm here today for
this live session with all of you at
wellness 360 but it's been good okay so
you know what I'm very excited and I'm
sure all our viewers are very excited to
actually learn something today that what
more one can do being at home and get to
be fit in fine so I'm just remind all my
viewers are watching us remember we had
asked you to get a towel ready so I hope
you have a towel with you
Amira pinky
liudmila and Avila will a be white which
music if you you have to have this you
also have to make sure you have a mat
which is important make sure you have a
bottle of water which is important to
cause your keep sipping on water you
make sure you have a tissue so we can
always kill up all your sweat
and no shoes and no socks that's
important
anything else he asked me that I'm
missing our chair yes very important
make sure you have a chair with you such
that you learn something better
this evening with wellness 360 at home
brought to you by ice yes you know box
okay don't stress about it I'll find a
way to substitute the chair for
something it's just the support so but
the towel is really important so grab a
towel any kind of towel your bath towel
it should be long don't let it be your
napkin it's a towel and I love the pink
color but and of course water to step on
and you know alright so there we go
water Aniki bunny it cherian get good
sleep it mad Jana get mad it W Annika
Tolia Jana key or shot me tissue so Toya
originally got so subtly at the average
I ate Yuki is wellness me something more
to learn or which esse to harden Tilly a
chub and I so ladies and gentleman
always watching us
let the fitness wellness begin here at
will less 360 at home brought to you by
icy SLO bar wait
Jasmina achieve Allah with the towel I
will show you what to do
your towel the little box 10 minutes the
towel is creepy because I thought you
know all of you sitting in this position
watching TV or on a computer you're
playing you know a game or whatever on
your phone sending messages they are all
grounded we are all sexy enough for
bodies I just want you to feel that
opening which is so so important so
we're going to do about 10 minutes of
the towel walk which is also gonna burn
your arms when you make your arms feel
and look good the second portion of my
workout is to work our lower bodies and
to make us just move and strengthen our
lower body which is so important and the
third 10 minute section of my workout
today is just focusing on your full body
movements we're gonna do different
things to open in the chest abdominal
which I'm sure some coaching here to
work the abdominals
be careful towel long
fold it into half
just let it drop pull the two ends hold
it into another half
now we'll leave this with one hand wrap
the towel at the center and start
twisting it in opposite directions just
twist and twist your towel
did you reach she is
just it's really nice and tight when you
all lose at the end I want you to hold
one end of the towel to your shoulder
and make sure your arm straight and that
is your grip hold the towel tight at
both the ends and then hand down on your
bottom
from there lift your shoulders and your
toes and if you toes and the shoulders
on an inhale and exhale
look over your toes head shoulders
picture not listing your views your toes
and the Front's even lift your toes and
shoulders exhale down shoulders x tilta
you want to talk I'm just going to show
you how weather PA and exhale up your
feet are together again imagine sliding
your back down wall inhale down exhale
exhale last one down exhale up from
there lift your right heel expressing
both of your right foot and lower it
down lift your left heel press into the
ball of the left foot and lower it down
right heel up stress into that all feel
the articulation of your foot that is I
think the feet are the most neglected
part of our body we never work it but
it's the most weight bearing part which
is so important to work
so all it needs is a little bit of
articulation to today and you're gonna
continue to do it as often as you can
from there
lift to the balls of your feet and lift
that knee up and back to the poles and
lower it down if to the balls of your
feet
don't let go of your Tom who bare
getting that I'll just move my desk
back to the feed and down this point go
ahead you heels up taking you head up
towards the ceiling and come down
try to go straight up and create your
spine inhale up exhale down now check
what's happening you heels when you're
going up I'll be able to keep them
together you want to keep it together so
that we want a midline of our body for
more lift up balance yourself keep your
heels together and lower down and lift
up and lower it down two more
repetitions lift up what that midnight
going for your calmness your chest your
head that's what you want to energy snow
and the last one let's go up and exhale
down now pull your shoulders back and
forward and back and two and four last
one and forward
now we've forgotten our towel holder
towel and pull it back muscles and used
in your back
Oh
[Music]
two holes by now Shona should be burning
or if they have not been holding the
towel
[Music]
together x11 exercise before we end
move onto your chest elbows elbows down
elbows ah
thus one elbows and take the arm up
no on the table down pull out our two
chests protect the elbows take the table
not the towel down pull it to chest
fruity one take it down let's propose it
el Moussa towel Street table elbows bent
elbows up towel push Tallulah elbows
down and extend to list and law and
rotate to extend to left to lower last
one extend and lift lower all the way
back one more time
and use the towel to wipe your sweat off
and then place it to the side and get me
a chair
[Music]
don't have a chair you can simply touch
the wall to get your position okay so
get your fingertips wonder what they're
all of you who have to check into
singles on the chair you're gonna stand
your feet together this two toes open
your legs into a Pilates B which is what
I call it where your knees are together
on your toes have turned out in that
position keeping your views together
gonna meanest up straight so you're
cuter office folio and also you see just
you and me he is fine imagine a wall and
you slide down the walls here against my
boss and I lifted my views up I will
just be sliding down the wall and my
knees oh oh my feet so those of you
whose needs her to skate your neck wider
and do the same movement you can even
have the option of not being on your
heels and being down with that's
uncomfortable for your knees but for all
of you can do it let's get into this
position and they are like spawn Eve
together
sipping up the inner thighs abdominals
are going to us up here and we're going
to take one hand out in front of us and
pass 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 1 2 3 4 this is
homeless
7 out 1 2 3 5 6 7 1 2 3 5 6 7 8 1 2 3 4
3 4 to change
oh boy
[Music]
you have to change - ah - singles one
don't forget six seven oh one change 100
- ah
[Music]
and then slowly
sound at the edge of your back
you
and it still
and inhale up and this time as you
exhale imagine people I avoid all the
walls of snow
hold up slow bend your knees extending
your knees when you nice-looking
Eugenie's extending your knees feel the
bounce your hamstring stretching extend
your knees then I mix them and then roll
back up putting your cooling abdominals
imagine is stacking up against an
imaginary wall behind you niente pigeons
are example over that imaginary beach
fall to the floor this time walk out
into an all-fours position from there
round your back to not keep any button
below leaving some catches off I'm gonna
extend your back to open your chest and
round your back look at your belly
button and open it shine it belly button
ah see that nice curve in your back and
then extend sign about creation your
actions feel amazing is friendship
series and the next
[Music]
1 2 3 5 7 9 10 13 14 15 16 17 18 19 20 5
so from this position you're gonna come
back mr. shields and come back into a
solid
lift your butt and lift your heels come
back into a circle
last one lift you over from there you're
gonna lift your right arm and left leg
and reach it out slowly back away and
opposite leg
[Music]
take your legs to the front
Jimmy's holding it off you nice clean up
don't lower down to your arms our city
only to Kansas tree and then use your
own extend your spine hold the knees
press into them
I'm in control
Oh
and two more slaw and clone
[Music]
in your repetitions cool will you write
me to your chest and straighten your
left leg out and switch and switch
and switch switch three four four three
two one
unions and rollin side to side
[Music]
look
if you heels take 44 make sure your
chest is open press if you hurt
last one up hold it
any one of the other person you know
Anna's switch legs press the heel of a
streamlining from mark and
[Music]
that was perfect
40 minutes workout I am NOT looking but
I'm sweating I'm sure everyone else must
be speeding by now you are sweating as
well yes means I will give you about a
two minutes breather no good I can go on
I know I think you need the visa I think
we all should get a 2 minute speed as
well breathe in don't bring too much
water
sip a little water such that you just
revitalize yourself questions after that
but gasping that was amazing that
somebody could actually do so much of
upper body workout just using a towel
I know that's great isn't it I mean I
love this workout because I mean you can
just use no equipment the thing is you
just have to want to move your body and
you can move it with so many things that
I really love the towel
we actually have really pretty towels we
make and we sell in the studio which
looks like this and the fancy and they
better or and you know that you hold
them better but having said that you can
just use a regular towel and you get the
same effect um depending on some people
Styles a slightly thick or sometimes so
what I'll do is uh I mean if i have
climbs who are sick you know the towels
I really think I'll just make them slice
them in the middle old towels of course
and then use that so that they fit in
the hand but it's it's a really amazing
workout for me and I think all my
clients love it is bruising it just
opens the upper part of your body so
beautifully and I think you know all of
us we need that so like a lot of times
the routine I did now I will use as a
warm-up before I start to work out with
clients just to get them to see you that
openness in their upper body and you
know shoulders and stuff and I was doing
it while we're teaching and I just spent
you know what it's so much more easier
now to get the perfect balance of both
arms stretching equally and not going
haywire so that's the best part is
standing in front of a mirror and you
know you have your arms you can see if
one shoulder is not activating and one
lap is not activating because the towel
won't be slip straight it will be
slightly you know tilted or sometimes
it's front and back so there are a lot
of things as an instructor that I see
happening with my clients upper bodies
that then I know I have to fix so it's a
really good tool to see where and how
upper bodies are functioning but I must
say thank you so much ask me that was
really amazing and I'm sure all our
viewers who are watching us back home or
wherever you are I'm sure you learn
something more today in terms of
wellness 360 at forum now we cannot get
into Q
they already asked me I'm perfectly
ready yeah okay the first question
that's coming is a perfect diet plan for
weight reduction very very open-ended
vast question because there are I mean I
have to know a way to have to know if
your lifestyle I have to know your
height I have to know whether you have
any conditions but in very simple terms
I don't eat fried food if you want to
lose weight don't have aerated water
don't have alcohol but sugar for me is a
complete no I haven't had sugar for five
years and I recommend sugars basically
poison to your body so I totally don't
recommend sugar so these are things that
you need to stay away from when you when
you're designing your meals make sure
that your meal has a little bit of fiber
it has a little bit of protein it has a
little bit of good cop and a little bit
of the fat your good fat can be an
avocado it can be coconut oil it can be
almonds you know so every meal and needs
to have bees and you need to have three
meals in the day which is your breakfast
lunch and dinner and if you're having
three full meals you have to try not to
snap it in between but if you're the
kind of person who likes to eat every
two hours then remember your breakfast
lunch and dinner needs to be smaller
meals
you can't like eat a big meal and then
one hour later want to eat something
else and your snacks again plan your
snacks because it's very easy when
someone tells you snacks and you see a
bowl of chips lying there you want to
eat it staying at home is worse because
be sleep with the kitchen so often that
no we pick up whatever's available and
they're always hungry so our plan your
snacks keep healthy things I keep a lot
of carrot sticks in my cup or in my
fridge I keep nuts in my fridge I don't
keep junk food from junk food if you
want to lose weight a big no-no junk
food if you wanna lose weight and of
course make sure you have three meals
and this follows
routine so that again of
getting extra fat now well and the
question coming from Nicolas
Bandopadhyay ah he's asking how to keep
fit and concentrate on mind white is
learning in education
can you repeat that for me please keep
it and concentrate at mind while
studying a while learning something -
right necklace that's right okay Nikki
let's shop
basically make your workouts much
shorter so that they don't take away the
energy that you then require our to
study so make them shorter and more
energetic like if you saw the workout we
did now it was a 30 minute workout it
worked
your entire body but it didn't get your
heart rate to a point where then you
need to calm down and you know but it
still felt worked out so choose workouts
which energize you and don't tire you
out so that then you have a fresh
combine to study that's an answer
Nikolas is one of the question coming
from by Charlie Wade was asking I wanted
to know if I have lights on the lightest
upper back area than just work as an
editor for webpage just wanted to know
what exercises would you recommend and
can I do Surya namaskara
so by shali your spondylitis is because
you're an editor and because you're
constantly bending over and you're
constantly on that laptop and you're
constantly inflectional our necks a head
actually weighs a lot okay it's like a
watermelon on top of your neck so where
what happens is this is the position we
need to have a head in right but when
you're working you go into this position
so you're constantly taking that heavy
weight and pulling it forward which is
making your spine has to work even
harder and it wants to pull it back but
you're weakening it by putting it here
so a great exercises so you would just
be doing chin tucks like just sitting up
with your shoulders down and tuck in
your chin back and teaching the neck to
hold the head up and teaching the head
where it needs to be another good thing
is when you're working on your computer
it needs to be at this level so that
when you walk you're here and you're not
here okay when you're looking at your
and a lot of times these days we have
smartphones so all our email travel
we're all here we actually need to fold
up a phone here to work so prop your
elbows on a table
safe another table try out your elbows
on the table so that your your opponents
in line with your face and you're
working this way and you're allowing
your head to be in alignment with your
spine a couple of the exercises I did
when I said look in a certain way
because we want the head to be in
alignment with the spine which is very
very important so know when just
exercises which of course you need to do
to strengthen one has this and one is
let you use even if you just use a towel
and put it here and press into it you
know and build that strength in your
neck and then have somebody hold towel
behind and push your head forward and
the same way sideways you know you just
need to strengthen those neck muscles
you do meet a lot of extension like a
swan which I ended my workout with and
strengthened that neck area before going
into getting into like exercises you
know focus on your strengthening work
your lower body work your abdominals
strengthen your neck before you start
doing our core body exercises right he
said yes we know we are so busy looking
at things that we do we forget about our
body postures and how we looking down
and up and I think there's small small
things if you keep in mind you can do
wonders with your body
am i right ask me totally and that's
what I I you know I I focus on when
clients come in and they want to do
these big things and you know achieve
these because I start at the very
foundation of where do we need we need
to build a foundation to make sure that
it's strong enough so that then whatever
you throw out your body your body is
able to you know deal with but if your
foundation is not a case you have
problem with your shoulder your network
you know your glute or something's not
firing you cannot move you will have an
injury book I work a lot with people on
just
fixing before you know moving ahead
alright so one last question you asked
me that's coming from me actually you
know some people really workout on
everyday basis and then you go to the
gym heavy weights and then this for six
months no workout which happens and what
it does to many people many men in fact
is that they happen to get their moves
and it increases so what are the quick
things that one can do at home in simple
workout that can reduce their moves so
the thing is why would someone stop
working out for six months you know if
you're working on and and I see a lot of
that happening when people go crazy and
do one and a half hour cause which I
know myth in you do one enough I work
out every day right Wow so what happens
is people get relief like I said they
want the bigger goals right so they go
crazy and they work out every day and
sometimes they work out seven days a
week and he'll work out for one not one
and a half two hours and then suddenly
they reach a plateau where they don't
feel like working out just the name Jim
irritates them you know oh something
happens to their wiring and they get
your pulse fire and then they stop
working on it and you start to gain in
fact I miss tend to lose muscle so I
don't stop working out and don't over
work out you know I am a firm believer
of having one day offs in the week one
day to do just nothing if you're lucky
enough and we're not in quarantined and
get a massage you know
just relax up do something that you
enjoy doing one day a week work out six
days a week
don't over kill yourself - just enough
workout that makes you feel good yes you
want to achieve that great body but at
the end of the day if you don't feel
good after God it's not gonna be you
know a life a lifetime thing that you're
gonna do like I believe Fitness is not a
destination it's a journey and if you
are going to stop and if for some reason
I mean these are
great things to hear and everyone's
saying it but sometimes our mind just
walks another way and we do it any which
way we know it's not good but we do it
because we think we are going to be that
one person who's gonna beat that you
know getting bored and getting fed up
and where that one person is gonna
continue doing that to our workout for
the rest of our life
know I've been in this profession for 29
years it doesn't work it has to be
something that is a part of your routine
and a routine needs to be something that
you can follow day after day but if you
do get set up of working on and not to
develop the fat that you're talking
about at leaves to 3 sets of 10 to 15
push-ups in a day you can do 5 push-ups
10 times a day you know just do five
push-ups wherever you are at a wall do
five push-ups it I mean that's the
easiest way to not get the fat around
you know or the areas that you don't
want but that's the simple sexist that's
the simplest excess explanation I can
give you plus don't eat junk that's why
it all falls down to that one thing
don't eat junk make sure you two working
out go easy on it give a day in a week
is to rest it down calm your body up and
much more in terms of being perfectly
well and make sure you're fit so you
asked me thank you so much for joining
us here at the Wellness 360 at home I
think we learned so much today that you
know what one need not really lifts
muscles and Bates you get it get fit I
think being at home by the means of
towel or chair you can actually get to
be having a better life than you usually
do so yeah thank you so much with him it
was amazing to be here at 360 wellness
and the life session and if you actually
go to my Instagram you see I do
exercises on the couch and bad
everywhere else so yeah we are it's
really easy to exercise it's actually
don't think of it as exercise think of
it as movement you know and it's just
movement like a
movement at 360 ICICI Lombard so great
thank you for inviting me to this
wellness and I really really enjoyed
myself I hope that everyone did do I did
what I thought would work for you so
thank you for having me stay safe stay
home and stay positive
that's right stay home stay positive is
one last word from you ask me crouched
Shiva turning aside wellness 368 or
brought to you by ICS hello Bart thank
you so so much
you asked me to bring with us it was
great having you that's why you learn so
much everyone watching us back home on
Facebook Instagram or zoom today you
learned that you can beat fit add the
best and the best version of you but
just by the means of using travel or
maybe by the means of a chair workout
but yes just do so such that you beat it
you be positive and all it takes is a
start so start right away thank you
again for joining us we will see you for
the next episode but for meanwhile just
do me one favor be fit be fine be nice
be happy be positive its wellness 360 at
home my name is Bertha Naposki I catch
me on Instagram as well follow me there
and you can know more about me thank you
so much for joining us we'll see you
next one for now have a great evening
and even better a day thank you so much
again